what do you do for a living? I
чем зарабатываете на жизнь так Я же
told you, I have my own
сказал у меня своя база
recreation center, I’m here so little, I’m missing I’m on the
отдыха меня тут так немножко я мичу я на
stock exchange now, I
бирже сейчас вот
bought a good deal, slashing us, the bizha
скупил неплохо сеча нас бижа
fell, in the sense that the bizha fell, the bizha fell, I
упала в смысле бижа упала бижа упала я
bought 400 now, well,
закупил ну
believe me, by the New Year I will have 800,
Поверь к Новому году у меня 800
hello  hi, let's
здравствуйте привет давайте нормально
talk normally Well, let's where are you from? I'm from
поговорим Ну давайте вы откуда Я из
Yaroslav Well, from the Yaroslavl region I'm from
Ярослав Ну из Ярославской области Я из
the city of Riga
города Рига
Latvia were once  in Riga No, I
Латвия были когда-то в Риге Нет я тоже в
wasn’t in Yarosla either. When I graduated from
яросла не был Дато когда я закончил
college I went to
институт Я поехал в
Riga. Well, I wanted to look for a job.
Ригу Ну поискать место работы хотелось
Well, I wanted to look there, but they didn’t hire me. And
Ну поискать там но только мне не взяли
who were you in your specialty? And then
А по специальности кто вы были а потом я
after a while I even realized damn
через некоторое время даже понял блин
how glad I was  I
как как я радше меня
was accepted and understood And what specialty did you graduate from?
взяли понял А Вы что заканчивали на
I was
я был
an institute at the Rybinsk Aviation
институт Рыбинского авиационного
Technological Institute, so And
технологического института так А
where
куда
did you want to
хотели
get a job? Well, what’s
устроиться Ну этим как
his name in the port of Talin, these well, the hooks that
его в порт талина этим ну крючки которые
according to Talani are
по талани
called Nestro
нестро называется
doesn’t matter, I understood correctly that you
неважно я я правильно понял что вы
graduated from Rybinsk aviation
закончили рыбинские авиационый
in short None of you took me from you
короче Никто меня из вас из вас не взя А
Why did you so
почему вы так
like Why did you graduate from Rybinsk
хо Почему вы так из Рыбинска закончили
aviation but not aviators decided to
авиационным но не авиаторам решили в
stay in Rybinsk
Рыбинске остаться
Arab apartment I wish they gave them to you
арабо квартира Мне нужна бы увас их
I had a wife and a child Well where
У меня же была жена ребнок Ну куда мне
could I go  I think I’ll somehow pass the
было деться думаю пройду как-нибудь
slip about
скольз про
Well, in order to get up damn it
Ну за то чтобы встать блин каким-то этим
somehow I gave everything for him
онм я же за него всё
and that And now and now I’m for your
отдавал и что А тепер а теперь я за вашу
Estonian  bureaucracy
эстонскую бюрократию
caress Well, Latvian,
ласку Ну Латыш
you are against
ты вы против
us Well, you
нас Ну
were left And now I’ll tell you
были остались А теперь я тебе скажу я
how long ago I remained Russian You won’t believe it,
Как ра я остался русским Ты не поверишь
all of Latvia is celebrating today that
у нас вся Латвия сегодня празднует что
you
ты
remained
остался
Latvian I’m Russian I’ll tell you brother
латви Я русский Я вот тебе скажу брата
We, too, now look all of Latvia
Мы тоже сейчас смотри вся Латвия
sighed  that you are Russian and in Russia and not
вздохнула что ты русский и в России а не
in Latvia Well, I don’t know Yes, no, not because
в Латвии Ну ну вот я не знаю Да нет не
we had so much before the collapse of the SR That’s why it
пото у нас до распада СР стоко Вот это
came in large numbers to the ports Yes from  You
понаехала в порты Да из Рыбинска ты себе
can’t imagine Rybinsk, I’ll tell you
не представляешь я тебе скажу
honestly Well, no, I don’t know Well,
по-честному Ну нет ну я не знаю Ну вот
you see what my fate was like, I didn’t
видишь какой как у меня судьба была я ве
want to work honestly I wanted, damn it,
хотел по-честному работать Я хотел блин
as if I had a higher education Do I
как будто у меня высшее образование было
really think hands won’t take me Well?
Неужели думаю меня руки не возьмут Ну
like those hooks there at your
типа в эти которые там крюки на вашем
port, damn they didn’t take me, they did
порту блин не взяли ни взяли вобще что
n’t even
даже не
take me, I didn’t even let you in. I’m for this, I’m for this, I’ll
подпустили я Я за это я вас за это я вас
never forgive you for this in life, I’ll be with
за это в жизнь никогда не прощ я буду
you, you understand how angry I am.  you
вам понимаешь у меня какая злость А ты
think that it’s not like that, of course everything, of
думаешь что не так конечно всё уж
course we are, well, we stand behind the wall and of course we won’t
конечно мы Ну да стоим за стеной и не
strain you, live as you want. Well,
будем конечно напрягать жите как хотите
by and large, you Think for yourself, if
Ну по большому счёту ты Подумай сам если
someday in my time, in my
когда-нибудь в моём времени в моём моём
desire, everything will be and I’ll be
желании всё будет ь я
honest,
те честно
but you see how  Well, honestly, Well,
Зато видишь как Ну да честно Ну Ну уж
that’s how it happened to me. They offended me so much
так вышло меня Настолько меня обиделись
how much they beat me with yours from yours.
сколько меня били с вашим с ваших
And
этих А
look, wait, they
смотри Подожди они
were RB next to me. Who beat you
меня были РБ сле Кто тебя бил
and got to yours when I’m like
и добрался до вашего этого когда мне как
me  I should have told you where they
я вот должен был сказать где тебя
beat you, so of course I didn’t rock you,
били вот дава конечно не скален вас всё
that’s okay, okay, we won’t be there,
да ладно что Ладно не будем там всё
let’s keep that in mind We won’t touch you either Well, we won’t touch you
давай та Имей в виду Мы вас тоже не
at all, so I
будем Ну совсем не тронем так чуть-чуть
just realized a little bit and Look, after
только понял а Смотри после того как
you don’t  found a job in Latvia Where did you
тебе ты не нашёл работу в Латвии Куда ты
go to
поехал
work Home Where Back back to Russia
работать Домой Куда Назад назад в Россию
well where
ну куда
exactly under under
именно под под
Yaroslav and work nya there I am I, I
Ярослав и работа ня там я же я же я
understand I am I then I went to my
понимаешь Я же я же я же потом уехал к
mother and then  I organized my own
маме а потом я организовал свою
workshop
мастерскую
And wait, why not Why didn’t they
А подожди а почему не Почему почему не
find a job there, why
нашли работу у себя там почему вам не
didn’t they give you a job there, didn’t they hire you there Well,
дали не взяли на работу вас там Ну
at first it didn’t work out like that Well why Well, okay, they
сначала не получалось так Ну почему Ну
didn’t like you in Latvia, they didn’t
ладно в Латвии вас не любили не взяли на
hire you, why were you in your native country?  They
работу а почему вас в родном Ярославле
didn’t hire them in Yaroslavl Well
не взяли на работу Ну
then, well, you understand, at first, when I was
потом Ну понимаешь сначала когда я туда
eager to go there to
рвался в
Latvia, those laws that I
Латвию тех законов которые мне были
needed. They weren’t
нужны Их не было
there, any kind of law on small
каких там закон о Малом
businesses, law on taxes. Well, it
предпринимательстве закон о налогах Ну
was different, there wasn’t perestroika yet,
по-разному было перестройки не было ещё
yes, yes  me, I’ve been trying to get to Latvia for 4
да да меня я же прорывался в Латвию 4
years. And what year was this
года А в каком это году было
something?
чтото Так
So then I jumped away from this and
вот потом я отпрыгнул от этого и
st.
ул а потом оказалось что можно в
cars that I knew
некоторые машины которые я же знал
well
хорошо
needed to be made by us and then it turned out that people
нужно делать имы и потом получалось что
from
из
St. Petersburg came to me for a lot of
Питера приезжали ко мне за большие
money and disappeared. Well, you
деньги девались Ну нормально
understand everything normally, that is, by and large,
всё понимаешь то есть по большому
yours is like
счёту ваша это как
his Baltic one,
его Прибалтийская
no one needs it
стала никому не нужна
Well, yes  yes, sorry Yes, that’s the
Ну вот да да извини Да так уж
big picture And what should we go
есть большому счёту А что нам поехали мы
there, we’ll do there Well, in general, in short, we are
туда там сделаем Ну в общем короче мы
mechanics on our side with
механики с нашей стороны стали с
mechanics on your side, that’s all
механиками с вашей стороны вот и всё Вот
That’s all, the whole war was limited to these
это вся война вся ограничилась вот эти
Cool Cool yeah question What do you
Прикольно Прикольно да вопро А как вы
think  where people live better now in
считаете где сейчас люди живут лучше в
Latvia or in
Латвии или в
Russia, of course in
Россией конечно в
Russia, can you explain with what? You do
России а можете объясните чем Даже даже
n’t even need to count. Yes, and why do you
и считать не надо Да а чем лучше вы
live better than in
живёте чем в
Latvia? Look, look around, I
Латвии Посмотри Посмотри вокруг я вот
see in your Circle  you can show me your
вижу на ваш Круг можете показать свою
apartment
квартиру
let me wonder how Russians live
давай мне интересно как русские живут
[music]
[музыка]
computer I have pictures
компьютер Вот у меня картины
hanging of women Ponya this is my Daughter
висят бабы Поня это Дочь
So what
Так что
else is there
ещ там
I have an apartment 40 MT 40 MT apartment
у квартира у меня 40 МТ 40 МТ квартира
Yes
Да
nuvi this is the apartment I
нуви вот такая вот э квартира Я только
only live in the corner  from your
Живу только в углу от своей
apartment, what else can you do? I didn’t quite
квартиры что тебя ещё можете Я не совсем
see the apartment, turn this
увидел квартиру разверните мне эту
apartment around for me. Show me. I’m not
квартиру ещё Покажите Я не
quite possible. Well, what else can you do? Well,
совсем можно Ну что те ещё кр что ещё ну
turn that side of the
разверните ту ту сторону
apartment at the back, turn it to
квартиры сзади разверните на
180° Yeah, that's it Yes, it's a really small
180° Ага всё Да действительно маленькая
apartment Well, then keep turning
квартира так А ну дальше дальше крутите
Where further I can and there
Куда дальше могу а там
Cord Yes, something obk in the other direction
Шнур Да что-то обк в другую сторону
so
так
oh so so
о так так
understood And this is yellow, is it just the light
понял А это жёлтая это просто свет такой
or is there a fungus on the ceiling Well, yes
или это там грибок на потолке Ну да у
I only have two
меня только два
plywood I have two lanterns shining I
фанер У меня два фонаря светят
understand
понял
if I have two lanterns the rest are not shining
б у меня два фонаря светят остальные не
Is this your private house or
А это у вас дом частный или
apartment This is my apartment I understand big
квартира Это моя квартира понял большой
But I go there to the room Alone to
А вот туда вот в комнату я ухожу Одна
sleep there are two more rooms  and a toilet, but what about
спать там ещё две комнаты и туалет а как
two rooms, how then are there 40
две комнаты как тогда 40
square meters in your apartment, it’s not like that in your
квадратов у ва не так у вас у вас
apartments, rooms are counted as two each
квартиры по две считаются
And we have a living room
комнаты А у нас гостиная
And how much is the total square footage of
И сколько у вас суммарная квадратура
your apartment of all rooms
вашей квартиры всех помещений
127 Well, this is more somewhere,
127 Ну это уже больше где-то
believe me Well, I
верь Ну мне хватает
understand enough  it doesn’t matter, it’s all [ __ ], I understand. What do you
понял неважно это всё фигня понял А чем
do for a living?
зарабатываете на жизнь
I told you, I have my own
Я же сказал у меня своя база
recreation center, there’s a lot of me here,
отдыха меня тут так немножко
I just bought us on the stock exchange, the
ями Я на бирже сейчас вот
bizha
скупил нас бижа
fell, in the sense, the bizha fell, the bizha  I fell
упала в смысле бижа упала бижа упала я
right now, I
сечас 400
bought 400 Well, 400 pieces
закупился Ну 400 кусков
Believe me, by the New Year I will have 800
Поверь к Новому году у меня 800 будет
what kind of shares did you buy for 400,000
что вы какие акции вы купили на 400.000
rubles I know which ones I’ll
руб я знаю какие я тебе
tell you Damn, this is the second time I’m meeting a stock exchange grandfather,
скажу Блин я второй раз биржевого деда
you know which ones you want I’ll
встречаю знаешь какие хочешь я тебе
tell you there’s such a company Yakovlev in Russia
скажу есть такая фирма Яковлев в России
Yakov
Яков
so this is a new fight fight of the new Russia
так это новый бой бой новой России
and Yak releases
а Як выпускает
these 21
эти 21
do take take
делае бери
now in general 28
бери сечас вообще 28
kopeck it will cost a kopeck  800 rubles not in
копе копе будет стоит 800 руб не в т в
10 not in 10 I understand correctly you
10 не в 10 я правильно понимаю вы
bought shares of the Yakovlev concern Yes
скупили акции концерна Яковлева Да
Yes I’m in the minus right now I bought it when they
Да я сечас в минусе я я купил когда они
were 68 And now they are now 30 minus
были 68 А сейчас они они сейчас 30 минус
in double minus Yes a good
в двойном мину Да хороший
minus more than minus 28 more than  at 50,
минус больше чем мину 28 больше чем в 50
well, the price of shares has fallen by half; in short, the price of
ну в два раза упала короче стоимость
shares will go up tomorrow, and
акций пове они завтра вверх больше а
what are the prerequisites for what they are?
какие предпосылки к тому что они
You say, I tell you, take it bye
за те Ты говор тебе говорю берись пока
bye
пока
cheap Well, you don’t want it as you want,
дешёвый Ну не хочешь как хочешь тобой ну
well, I’ll wait until it drops to 10
мне что я подожду когда она упадёт до 10
rubles
руб
and wait Because they were 25 when
да ждать Потому что 25 они были когда
they were generally at zero, you can’t wait for 28 -
они были вообще в нуле не дождёшься 28 -
that’s
это
a minus, not you, the graph for 7 years,
минус не ты график за 7 лет
look at they
посмотри они 25
were 25 for 7
были за 7
years  no no I’ll just take my brother It’s
лет не не брата просто буду забирать
just that people will take it what a minus
Просто народ будет забирать какой минус
this is a rare
это редкий
case Act bro and you’ll be on
случай Действуй братан и ты всё время на
your
своём
American BNM all the time You’ll make good money with your money
бнм американском Будешь свои деньги
And what else are you  bought shares
хорошо А какие ты ещё акции покупал
invest in Boeing invest in Boeing or
вкладывай Боинг вкладывай в Боинг или
there Je
там Дже
Where are you yes maybe yes well I don’t have
Куда ты да может быть да ну я не имею
that many shares Can you tell me what
столько акций А можете сказать в какие
other shares you invested in sorry well sorry
вы ещё акции вкладывали извини ну извини
I’m just telling you mate where to
я тебе просто говорю мате гово куда
invest You don’t want to well
вкладывать Не хочеш ну
excuse me now  68 bought I'm in
извини у меня сейчас по 68 куплены Я в
the red but they'll be back by the end of the year
минусе но они к концу года вернутся
then even more
потом ещ ше
Sing I'll still win Believe me I'm at a loss I'm
Пой я ещё выиграю Поверь я я накладе я
not nervous I'm there 4
не нервничаю я там 4
million Let it not be this Boeing  this is our
миллион Пускай не этот Боинг это наш
Russian fighting
русский бои
Vern And your Russian is
Верн А ваш русский бо
not and therefore you know why why but
не а потому знаешь почему почему а
because I believe in it You don’t
потому что я в него верю Вот ты не
believe in it you generally only believe in the
веришь ты ты вообще веришь только в
American fight And I believe in the Russian And I
американский бой А я верю в русский А я
believe in the Russian Why Because I’m a
верю в русский Почему Потому что я
Russian person  I believe in the Russian fight Well,
русский человек я верю в русский бой Ну
he won’t win, and even with him, but I still
не выиграет он да и с ним но всё равно я
believe in him I understand because I’m
верю Понял потому что я я
Russian That’s how it turned out for me
русский Вот так вот так вот меня вышло
So the Russian Russian Boeing was lucky with
Так россий российским боингом повезло с
investors Well, that’s how fate led  I led him that way,
инвесторами Ну так судьба повела так уж
but still believe
повела но всё равно верить
him. Well, it just happened and that’s all, I
него Ну так уж вышло и всё я вот только
just realized that we Latvians
что понял что мы латыши в се в конце
lost such a nugget in the late seventies, I didn’t
семидесятых потеряли такой самородок не
ask for it, but what’s your name,
просил а ты же как тебя зовут
Andris Andris? And for me, Andrey,
андрис андрис А мне Андрей
we’re
пове мы
like that, it’s very difficult to defeat us.  it’s
такие нас победить очень
almost
трудно почти
unrealistic
нереально просто
it’s just that we can we can
пове что мы можем мы можем
take me like that I wouldn’t regret my life That’s
так меня взять я бы не пожалел жизни Вот
it Well, come on
что Ну вот давай
Andry,
Андрю
go but it’s necessary I would take it
иди но это нужно Я бы взял в бы
all
всё
climax you’re ready for Russia I’ll go  I'm
кульминация ты готов за Россию я пошёл я
ready for Russia Yes, look, you believe in
ты готов за Россию Да смотри ты веришь в
Russian Boeing And I believe in American
Российский Боинг А я верю в американские
tomahawks I believe that the day will come when
томагавки Я верю что придёт день когда
they will fly to Moscow
они полетят на Москву
Peter Rostov Novosibirsk
Питер Ростов Новосибирск
Vladivostok And I believe that one
Владивосток И я верю что один
will fly to
полетит
some God-given village in the Yaroslavl
какую-то Богом деревню Ярославской
region and meet there
области и встретит там
the Great Believer  in
Великого верующего в
Boeing That's how all the tomahawks come from all
Боинг Вот так все томагавки со всех
sides
сторон
and the lights go out. He was lucky
и гаснет
with investors, people
свет Повезло ему с инвесторами людям так
like it, comment, write on  mi instag I
лайк писка комент пись на мий instag Я
don’t know why this is why you are there to
не знаю для чего це то для чего тоб там
marvel at the office Ale for you this is one
дивитись на офес Але для тебе це один
two or three clicks Ale you trimae me and I
два або три клика Але ты тримае мене и я
will be KTA va in me there Kupa fouls and in
буду КТА ва в мене там Купа фолов и в
me there will be a cool mood to robiti
мене буде класный настрий щоб робити
Novi cool video  subscribe to my
Нови крути видео подпишись на мий
Instagram popk Andriy
Instagram попк Андрий вот
like this, let me check for you
так давай я тебя чекаю